# Furkan Tunalı Résumé

## Summary

I've been developing the web whether it's front-end, back-end, or designing things in multidisciplinary ways, mentoring, consulting or handling clients more than ten years.

As years went by and I've become more enthusiastic and experienced, I honed my skills within the projects, companies or clients that I've worked on the web field without strict limiting my area of work.

More recently, my primary focus has leaned towards developing software with JavaScript besides building and managing front-end architectures.

## Info

Fullname: Mustafa Furkan Tunalı

**Available working permits:** 4 years of Blue Card EU Residential and Working Permit holder and Turkish Citizenship

Current residency: Berlin

### Contact

• Web: FurkanTunali.com

• E-mail: mail@furkantunali.com

• Phone: +49 174 6492854

LinkedIn

• GitHub

## Experiences

• Front-end Team Lead at Groupe Chantelle, Digital Lab, Berlin

### 08/2017 - 12/2018

#### Some of my tasks were:

- Managing and being responsible for the actions of Front-end team.
- HR, interview, boarding and hiring process
- Modernizing front-end architecture without losing existing functionalities and values.
- Making sure codebase is improved and streamlined.
- o Implementing code quality assuring tools and automated of tests.
- Implement dev-ops tools and a new eco-system to act develop faster.
- Helping with the conversion from monolith systems into separated microservices when possible.
- Following Agile methods.
- Reviewing codes.
- Migrating from Front-end to being a Full-stack team.
- Mentoring, inspiring, guiding or helping front-end team when possible.
- Helping to achieve being data-driven and implementing A/B testing solutions.
- Making sure the projects will be fitted into sprints and acting if they are not going as planned.
- Tracking the development of UI library for connecting UX team and Front-end team components as a bridge.

### Some of the technology and services that I used so far:

- Node, Magento, WebPack, React, GraphQL, Redux, FlowType, AWS,
  Koa, MongoDB, Babel, Functional Programming, Atlassian tools, Github
- Universal JavaScript Engineer at Pixsy GmbH, Berlin

#### 01/2017 - 08/2017

#### My responsibilities were:

- Delivering new features on both ends with using JavaScript.
- Delivering code with the unit, integration and E2E covered tests.
- Maintaining or migrating existing features.
- Developing and maintaining micro-services.
- Improving our architecture and stack when its possible.
- Integrating and maintaining data on Mongo, Stripe and SalesForce.
- Keeping an eye on app health with Heroku and Sentry reports.
- Following KANBAN with some Agile methods.
- Reviewing codes from our team's pull requests.
- Following our code conventions and guidelines.

#### Some of the technology and services that I used:

- Node, Lambda/Serverless, React, Redux, FlowType, AWS, WebPack, Webpack Isomorphic Tools, Koa, MongoDB, Babel, HighlandJS, SalesForce API, Mixpanel, Mocha, Chai, Yadda, Webdriver.io on top of Selenium, Stripe API, Sentry, Github
- Software Architect and JavaScript Developer at <u>Talented</u>
  <u>Square, CA</u>

#### Some of the projects:

 Front-end development for a giant multinational retail corporation's online wholesale seller portal which cannot disclose its name but feel free to contact for the details.

**Some of the project skills:** JavaScript, Angular, AMD, Gulp, CSS, SCSS, HTML and small of amount of Maven and Jetty.

 Performance and architectural improvements and JavaScript development to an e-commerce website to the same company described above.

**Some of the project skills:** Browser and mobile optimisation, JavaScript, Backbone, AMD, CSS, jQuery, HTML and Ant.

 Architectural design and javascript development for a new recruiting startup project.

**Some of the project skills:** architectural decisions, JavaScript, LoopBack, Webpack, Gulp, MySql, React, Redux, HTML, SCSS.

Founder, full stack web developer and designer at NOD studios,
 Istanbul

11/2012 - 07/2015

### Some of the projects:

Web development and design for <u>Gym & Tonic</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

Web development for <u>Silent + Blessed</u>

Some of the project skills: Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache.

Web development and design for <u>Mirjam Schmitt</u>

- **Some of the project skills:** Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache, Wordpress, Wordpress JSON API.
- Web development and design and UX consultancy for <u>Les Benjamins</u>
  Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Mockup, Design, JavaScript, HTML, LESS, CSS, CanJS, Mustache, CakePHP.
- Web development, design, mobile app design, UX design and refactoring legacy code for <u>etiqadd</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

Social web app design and gamification for <u>Gripati</u>

Some of the project skills: Wireframing, Design, JavaScript, AMD, PHP, Codelgniter

Front-end mobile web development for <u>LigTV</u>

Some of the project skills: Mobile optimisation, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Internal website design and full stack web development for <u>Ülker</u>
  Some of the project skills: PHP, CakePHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Server side web RSS aggregator API development for a mobile app of <u>MB</u>
  <u>Apps</u>

Some of the project skills: CakePHP, PHP

Full stack web development for <u>Umut Üzümleri</u> movie

Some of the project skills: Design, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- Open source projects and libraries at <u>Github</u>
- Full stack web developer at FOX International Channels, Istanbul

01/2012 - 12/2012

Development of some social app and microsite web development for some clients including:

<u>Samsung Turkey</u>, <u>National Geographic Turkey</u>, <u>Nokia Turkey</u>, <u>True Blood TV show</u>, <u>Glee TV Show</u>, <u>TerraNova TV show</u>

• Front-end developer and designer at projectz, Istanbul

06/2011 - 12/2011

Front-end coding, refactoring and web design for startup project <u>yardimlazim.com</u>

• Full stack developer at Manajans / JWT, Istanbul

05/2009 - 06/2011

Development of websites, CMS development, online communities, social apps and microsites for some clients including:

Miller, GncTurkcell / Turkcell, Eston, First, Bomonti, Efes, TeraBrokers (Formerly TeraMenkul)

• Front-end developer at <u>Tribal DDB Worldwide Istanbul(formerly Manadigital)</u>

03/2009 - 05/2009

Front-end development for some clients including:

patlican / avea, TTNET

 Full stack developer at Ping Digital Agency Istanbul(formerly OnKaplan)

05/2008 - 03/2009

### Garanti, TTNET

 Designer, front-end and Flash developer at Koçak Dizayn, Istanbul

05/2008 - 03/2009

Design, concept art creation, front-end development and illustration for an online art community startup.

Designer and front-end developer at MedyaNova, Istanbul

05/2005 - 02/2007

Design and front-end web development for various web projects mostly regarding travelling, hotel and hotel franchise clients like <u>Best Western</u> <u>Hotels</u>.

Internship at MedyaNova, Istanbul

04/2005 - 05/2005

### Skills

- Programming & Development
  - Software & Markup Languages
    - JavaScript / ECMAScript,
      EcmaScript 2016 / ES6,
      EcmaScript 2017 / ES7 advanced
    - Node.js advanced
    - PHP advanced
    - HTML / HTML5 / xHTML advanced
    - CSS / CSS3, less, SASS / SCSS advanced
    - Python beginner
    - Ruby beginner

- <u>SQL</u> advanced
- Familiar patterns / conventions: FP, Isomorphic / Universal Javascript, TDD, BDD, MVC, MVVM, OOP, Prototypal OOP, OLOO, AOP, ES6 Modules, AMD, CommonJS, Semantic Versioning
- Other: Bash, ASP, .NET, C, C++, PIC

### Tools

#### Some of the frameworks

- RxJS (beginner)
- Serverless for Lambda (advanced)
- Koa (intermediate)
- React (advanced)
- Redux (advanced)
- Flux (intermediate)
- Angular (advanced)
- Backbone (advanced)
- CanJS (advanced)
- polymer (intermediate)
- Aurelia (beginner)
- <u>express</u> (intermediate)
- LoopBack (advanced)
- CakePHP (advanced)
- lithium (intermediate)
- Codelgniter (intermediate)

#### Databases

- RethinkDB beginner
- MongoDB advanced
- MySQL advanced
- <u>SQLite</u> advanced

### Libraries and Miscellaneous Tools

Flow Type, Atom, npm, Homebrew, Babel, gulp, Jest, Chai Assertion Library, webpack, HighlandJS, WebStorm, Protractor, jQuery, RequireJS, Underscore.js / lodash, git, PM2, Wordpress, IBM API Connect, Bower, SystemJS, jspm, composer, pip, gem, Apache Http Server, PhoneGap, Appcelerator, fish, Bash

#### APIs and Services

Heroku, AWS (Amazon Web Services), SalesForce, Stripe, Mixpanel, Facebook, Twitter, Shopify, Flickr, Tumblr, WP REST API, SoundCloud, Pinterest

### Operating Systems

OS X, Ubuntu, Windows (Using it for playing some video games)

### Design

- Web Design on the browser
- UI Design
- Wireframing / Mockup Design
- Responsive Design
- Ul Design
- Web UX
- Branding / Identity
- Print Design

#### Tools

- Adobe Photoshop advanced
- Sketch beginner
- Adobe Illustrator advanced
- Adobe Fireworks intermediate

### Languages

- Turkish native
- English advanced

### Education

• Computer Programming and Technology at Kadir Has University

2004 - 2008

### Sehremini Anadolu High School

### Interests

- DJ and Founder at AmbientData
- Contributing back to an Open source
- Experimenting with side-projects
- Sci-Fi books, movies etc.
- Exploring Typography
- Photo manipulation
- Travelling
- Exploring Craft Beer and Coffee
- Video games
- Any kind of nerd activity